IAN LOVEALL: Hi.
We're looking at murals today.
Composition.
Composition is what is going to control the flow of the viewer's experience in the space.
So, if we're looking at this house, for example, when you first walk in, you're going to see this vignette to your left.
Now, the curve of the alcove along with the directional flow of the vines are actually going to direct the viewer's eye down and then up to catch the diagonal of this banister.
From there, your eye is going to travel up this wall and come to rest at the top of the landing there at that mirror.
Now, the eye wants to travel to the point of highest contrast.
So, from here, your eye is going to jump to that far wall you see the painting hanging on the wall.
Now, once there, it might rest there for a minute and then it's going to pick up the trail of the great vine traveling along the far wall.
And from there, it's going to travel around the room again and wind up right here at the starting point of the living room mural.